A Guide to the Business Archives of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1904-1979 (1914-1961)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Topical & Subject Files 1899-1979, n.d. (Carton 13-26)
  - Union Tank Car Company 1935-1944 (Carton 24)
  - Union Trust Company 1940-1944 (Carton 24)
  - United Combustion Corporation 1935-1938, 2 folders (Carton 24)
  - United States Railroad Administration 1918-1919 (Carton 24)
  - Uranium 1953-1955 (Carton 24)
  - Virginia Blue Ridge Railway--Financial Statements [1914]-1947, 7 folders (Carton 25)
  - Virginia Chemical Corporation 1936-1951, 3 folders (Carton 25)
  - Virginia Clay 1930-1955, 3 folders (Carton 25)
  - Virginia Department of Highways 1931-1956 (Carton 25)
  - Virginia State Auditor of Public Accounts 1915-1920 (Carton 25)
  - W Miscellaneous 1931-1944 (Carton 25)
  - W.E. Buford & Company 1954 (Carton 25)
  - W.W. Robertson 1932-1936 (Carton 25)
  - War Production Board 1942-1944, 2 folders (Carton 25)
  - Willis E. Waterman 1934-1937 (Carton 25)
  - Wayne Lumber Company 1920-1922 (Carton 25)
  - Western Union Telegraph Company 1936-1944 (Carton 25)
  - James C. White, Tennessee Eastman Corporation 1930-1938 (Carton 26)
  - Wilmington, Brunswick & Southern Railroad Company, E.F. Middleton, Receiver 1941-1943 (Carton 26)
  - Gordon Woodson 1936-1956 (Carton 26)
  - Woodson Lumber Company 1917-1923, 3 folders (Carton 26)
  - Y-Z Miscellaneous 1938-1944 (Carton 26)
- Financial & Administrative Records 1914-1961, n.d. (Carton 26-41)
  - Accident Reports to the Interstate Commerce Commission 1933-1940, 2 folders (Carton 26)
  - Accident Reports to the Virginia State Corporation Commission 1933-1940 (Carton 26)
  - Annual Reports to the Interstate Commerce Commission 1920-1933, 3 folders (Carton 26)
  - Annual Reports to the Virginia State Corporation Commission 1916-1934, 19 volumes (Carton 26)
  - Bank Passbooks ca. 1915-1931 (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--De Priest Bank, Massie's Mill, Va. 1930-1932, 3 folders (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--De Priest Bank, Massie's Mill, Va.--Leftwich Timber Company 1917, 1930-1931 (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--First National Bank of Nelson County, Lovingston, Va. 1933-1944, 7 folders (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--Miscellaneous 1916-1927 (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--Riggs National Bank--Leftwich Timber Company ca. 1921-1930, 2 folders (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--Riggs National Bank--Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1921-1930, 3 folders (Carton 27)
  - Bank Statements--Union Trust Company of the District of Columbia 1943-1944 (Carton 27)
  - Bills 1914-1917, 1926-1933, 21 folders (Carton 27-28)
  - Bills--Expenses 1915-1916, 8 folders (Carton 28)
  - Bills--Expenses--Frank O. Lathrop 1915 (Carton 28)
  - Buildings & Bridges--Accounts ca. 1924-1944, 3 folders (Carton 28)
  - Car Repairs--Accounts 1925-1943 (Carton 28)
  - Car Service Reports 1934-1939 (Carton 28)
  - Daily Report of Cars on Hand 1944-1945, 2 folders (Carton 29)
  - Daily Report of Cars on Hand--Piney River 1944-1945, 6 folders (Carton 29)
  - Embargoes #277-1500 1916-1918, 12 folders (Carton 29)
  - Freight Claims & Complaints 1915-1923, 2 folders (Carton 29)
  - Freight Claims 1923-1943, 22 folders (Carton 30)
  - Fuel for Locomotives--Accounts 1930-1944 (Carton 30)
  - General Office Expenses 1915-1944, 3 folders (Carton 30-31)
  - Iron Mine--Accounts 1940-1942 (Carton 31)
  - Locomotive Repairs--Accounts ca. 1929-1944, 3 folders (Carton 31)
  - Machinery & Tools--Accounts 1924-1944, 8 folders (Carton 31)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts 1915-1939, n.d., 2 folders (Carton 31)
  - Monthly Report of Revenues & Expenses 1921-1923 (Carton 31)
  - Oil & Wastes--Accounts 1925-1944 (Carton 31)
  - Order for Cars 1941-1944, 3 folders (Carton 31)
  - Payrolls of the Leftwich Timber Company 1922-1925 (Carton 31)
  - Per Diem Accounts 1916-1928, 1935-1944, 26 folders (Carton 32)
  - Railroad Ties--Accounts 1925-1944, 7 folders (Carton 33)
  - Receipt Book 1916-1922 (Carton 33)
  - Report of Cars Handled 1947-1956, 2 folders (Carton 33)
  - Road Maintenance--Accounts 1941-1944, 6 folders (Carton 33)
  - Statement of Carloads Handled 1954-1961, 13 folders (Carton 33-34)
  - Telephone Accounts 1925-1944, 4 folders (Carton 34)
  - Time Slips for Workers 1930, 1943-1947, 86 folders (Carton 34-38)
  - Traffic Expense 1929-1944, 16 folders (Carton 38-39)
  - Vouchers 1914-1924, 45 folders (Carton 39-41)
  - Vouchers--Alphabetical Listing on 4 x 6 cards ca. 1917-1935, 3 folders (Carton 41)
- Unfoldered Buills of Lading; Delivery Receipts; & Telegrams 1916-1932, n.d. (Carton 42-48)
  - Bills of Lading & Delivery Receipts 1916-1929 (Carton 42-47)
  - Packets of Telegrams 1916-1932, n.d. (Carton 47-48)
- Bound Volumes & Oversize Materials 1904-1944, n.d. (Carton 49-52)
  - Bank Registers--Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1915-1935, 28 volumes (Carton 49)
  - Bank Registers--Leftwich Timber Company 1914-1920, 1926-1930, 7 volumes (Carton 50)
  - Bank Registers--Tye River Timber Company 1917-1924, 1920-1934, 4 volumes (Carton 50)
  - Daily Desk Calendar 1936 (Carton 50)
  - Day Books for the Leftwich Timber Company 1922-1926, 2 volumes (Carton 50)
  - Day Books for the Tye River Timber Company 1922-1930, 3 volumes (Carton 50)
  - Index to Correspondents & Companies n.d. (Carton 50)
  - Journals of the Leftwich Timber Company 1913-1943, 4 volumes (Carton 50)
  - Journals of the Tye River Timber Company 1913-1944, 4 volumes (Carton 51)
  - Ledger ca. 1924 (Carton 51)
  - Ledger of the [Leftwich Timber Company ?] 1913-1944 (Carton 51)
  - Ledgers of the Tye River Timber Company 1913-1942, 2 volumes (Carton 51)
  - Miscellaneous Memoranda & Account Books 1934-1935, n.d., 3 volumes (Carton 51)
  - Sectional Field Book n.d. (Carton 51)
  - Telegram Book fo the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1915-1917 (Carton 51)
  - Trial Balance Book for the Leftwich Timber Company and the Tye River Timber Company 1920-1925 (Carton 51)
  - Scrapbook of Leftwich Timber Company Bond Coupons 1914-1918 (Carton 52)
  - Scrapbook of Tye River Timber Company Bond Coupons 1915-1918 (Carton 52)
  - Tyro Development Company Profile of the Tye River Railroad 1912 June 15, long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Revised Profile of Emily's Gap Route Progress Report 1916 April 30, long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Profile of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1916 December 31, long rolled graph (5 sheets) (Carton 52)
  - Untitled Graph n.d., long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Profile of Emily's Gap Revision n.d., long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Summary of Mile No. 1-12 n.d., long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Revised Profile of Emily's Gap n.d., long rolled graph (Carton 52)
  - Voucher Books 1914-1937, oversize bound volume (6 volumes)
  - Voucher Register No. 1, Virginia Blue Ridge Railway Company 1915 September-1924 December, oversize bound volume
    matching vouchers no. 1-5081 in cubics 39-41
  - Payrolls of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1914-1926 (Box S-51)
  - Luck Construction Company, Contractor, Roanoke, Va.--Detail Statements of Contract Work Done for the V.B.R.R. 1915-1916 (Box 51)
  - Emily's Gap Revisions--Original Cross Sections n.d., 36 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Emily's Gap Revisions--Final Cross Sections n.d., 46 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Original Cross Sections of Revision on L.K. Witt n.d., 13 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Sections of Ballast Pit n.d., 5 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Ditches n.d., 6 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Graph Paper Drawings re the Construction of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway, including Cut & Fill, Length, Trestle, Height, Excavation, Summary of Miles No. 11-12, and Embankment n.d., 10 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Diagram of a Gate and Archway n.d., 2 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Original Cross-Sections of Fill on Macon Page Property, Hilton Bridge n.d., 3 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Original Cross-Sections of Revision at Big Rock n.d. (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Sections of Under Grade Crossing on Paulus Massie n.d. (Box T-15)
  - Original Cross-Sections of "Y" at Tye River n.d., 2 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Original Cross-Sections of "Y" at Massie's Mill--East & West Leg n.d., 2 sheets (Box T-15)
  - Road Crossings n.d. (Box T-15)
  - Plat of Leftwich Timber Company Land near Alhambra, Nelson County 1914, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from Mrs. W.W. Terry 1915 February, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from T. Hilton Whitehead 1915 February, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from heirs of Cubus and Rebecca Whitehead 1915 February, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from W.H. Whitehead 1915 February, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from E.D. Slaughter 1915 February, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Rail Drilling, E.C. Sherwood, N.Y. 1915 February, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from Simon Wood 1915 March, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. above Woodson, Nelson County 1915 April, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from William Perkins, Nelson County !915 April, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. above Rose Mills, Nelson County 1915 April, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. above Woodson, Amherst County 1915 August, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from E.D.Slaughter, Amherst County 1915 September, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from Henry Anne Page, Nelson County 1915 October, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. on the Adam Garland Place, Nelson County 1915 November, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat showing land required for Right of Way by V.B.R.R. from John Demasters, Nelson County 1915 November, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Land Deeded by John Slaughter to E.D. Slaughter in Amherst County 1916 April, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. at Little Piney River, Amherst County 1916 May, blueprint sheet (3 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the V.B.R.R. above Lowesville, Amherst County 1916 May, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Cross-Section showing County Road Crossing of the Leftwich Timber Company Tramway 4 & 4.5 miles above Woodson, Nelson County 1916 December, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Map Showing Approximate Location of Real Estate north of Roseland in Amherst County 1931 March, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Map Showing Proposed Location of Railroad from Parr's Siding to a Point on the Property of Dr. J.B. Woodson 1942 May 8, blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Map of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railroad Total Mileage, 18.87 miles n.d., blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Outline Map of 83,000 Acre Timber Tract Situated in Bath & Alleghany Counties, Va. n.d., blueprint sheets (Box T-15)
  - "A" Line Cut & Fill Totals n.d., blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Plat of Martin Property, 135 Acres n.d., blueprint sheet (3 sheets) (Box T-15)
  - Railroad Track Scale n.d., blueprint sheet (Box T-15)
  - Map of Lands in Amherst County, Virginia, on the Headwaters of Piney River, Property of Clinton DeWitt and J. Steward Walker, Lynchburg, Va. 1904, blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Plat Showing Land Required from George Hilton by Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1915 January 7, blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Plat Showing Land Required for Right of Way from the James Dickey Estate by the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1915 May, blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Heavy Turntable of the Southern Railway Company, Re-erected by Cunningham of Winston-Salem 1915, blueprint sheet (2 sheets) (OS Tray)
  - Untitled Graph Diagram n.d., blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Timber Location Map for Taylor, Madison, & Lafayette Counties, Florida n.d., blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Graph of Railroad Elevation for [Mile No. 1] of the V.B.R.R. n.d., blueprint sheet (OS Tray)
  - Railroad Track Scale n.d., blueprint sheet (3 sheets) (OS Tray)
  - Estimate of Emily's Gap Revision 1915 August (OS Tray)
  - Progress Profile "Old Line" 1916 June 30, 2 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Profile of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1917 January (OS Tray)
  - U.S. James Company, Inc., Newark, N.J. Blueprints of Preliminary Plan for Ore Crushing & Magnetic Separeating Plant; Side Elevation of Mill Building for Dominion Minerals, Inc. at Piney River, Va.; Detail of Wood Silo Bases; Topographic Survey of Mill Site at Piney River, Va.; Foundation Detail for Grinding & Separating Plant of Dominion Minerals, Inc. 1937-1938, 9 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Property of Dr. J.B. Woodson near Lowesville, Nelson County, Va. n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Plat of Georgia Land & Livestock Company, McIntosh County, Georgia n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Untitled Graph Diagrams n.d., 5 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Profile of Emily's Gap on Graph Paper n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Profile of Jack's Hill n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Summary of Elevations, Mile No. 1-12 with Landowners adjoining the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway Listed n.d., 7 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Profile & Alignment of Emily's Gap Route n.d., 2 sheets (OS Tray)
  - "Old" & "New Line" Elevations for the V.B.R.R. n.d., 2 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Revised Profile of Emily's Gap Route n.d., 2 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Profile of Emily's Gap Revision n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Estimate of Emily's Gap Revision 1915 August (OS Tray)
  - Profile of Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1916 December 31, 8 sheets (Box 2, OS Tray)
  - Profile of Emily's Gap Revision n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Profile of Virginia Blue Ridge Railway n.d., 8 sheets (OS Tray)
  - Graph of "Old Line" and "New Line" n.d. (OS Tray)
  - Untitled Graph Paper n.d. (Oversize 9)